A Guide to the Black Appalachians Oral History Project, 1991
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Black Appalachians Oral History Project, 1991
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms91-019
0.4 cubic feet, 2 boxes, 8 folders, 25 cassette tapes
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Scope and Content Information
The Black Appalachians Oral History Project consists of approximately twenty-five taped interviews conducted by Dr. Michael Cooke of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University concerning black life in Appalachia, especially in Montgomery County, Virginia. The interviewees represented communities such as Blacksburg, Christiansburg, Elliston, Riner, Shawsville, and Wake Forest. Transcripts are currently available for six of the interviews.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into two separate parts: documents and taped interviews. Both sections are arranged in alphabetical order.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.)
Genre and Form Terms:
Oral histories (document genres)
Contents List
- Project Documentation 1991 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Disks (Box-folder 1-2)
- Pack, W. Wayman March 11, 1991 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Price, Christine P. March 4, 1991 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Smyth, Ellison A. March 5, 1991 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Smyth, Ellison A. March 5, 1991 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Wade, James C. March 12, 1991 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Wade, Sarah J. March 14, 1991 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Bannister, Frank T. February 26, 1991, 2 cassette tapes (Othertype 2-1)
- Bryson, Roxie Ida March 14, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-2)
- Burford, Alexander
  See entry for Burns, Leola
- Burns, Leola March 11, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-3)
- Dobbins, Rice March 2, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-4)
- Dow, James
  See entry for Scott, Valiere
- Holmes, Rosa Thomas March 13, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-5)
- Johnson, Charles A. March 3, 1991, 3 cassette tapes (Othertype 2-6)
- Lester, Elizabeth
  See entry for Lester, Thompson V., Sr.
- Lester, Thompson V., Sr. February 27, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-7)
- Lewis, Walter H. March 14, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-8)
- Morgan, William Burrell February 25, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-9)
- Pack, Cora
  See entry for Pack W. Waymon (A)
- Pack, J. Homer March 13, 1991, 2 original tapes plus 1 copy (Othertype 2-10)
- Pack, J. Waymon (A) March 11, 1991, 1 original tape plus 1 copy (Othertype 2-11)
- Pack, J. Waymon (B) March 11, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-12)
- Price, Christine P. March 4, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-13)
- Scott, Mason
  See entry for Scott, Valerie
- Scott, Valerie March 16, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-14)
- Sherman, Homer C. March 13, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-15)
- Sherman, James F. March 11, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-16)
- Symth, Ellison A. March 5, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-17)
- Wade, James C. March 12, 1991, 1 original tape plus 1 copy (Othertype 2-18)
- Wade, Sarah J. March 14, 1991, 1 original tape plus 1 copy (Othertype 2-19)
- Wright, Rev. Kenneth B March 19, 1991, 1 cassette tape (Othertype 2-20)